vantagefx.com 2017-12-08

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
VANTAGE FX PTY LTD                                                         How We Collect Personal Information
                                                                           Vantage FX collects personal information in a number of ways, including:
Our Commitment
                                                                                 ♦     directly from you, when you attend a face-to face interview;
Vantage FX Pty Ltd ("Vantage FX", "we", "our", "us") is committed to
providing you with the highest levels of client service. We recognise that
                                                                                 ♦     directly from you, when you provide information through a
                                                                                       data collection form;
your privacy is very important to you. The Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and the
“private sector amendments” contained in the Privacy Amendment                   ♦     directly from you, when you provide information by phone;
(enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012 (Cth) sets out a number of                     and
Australian Privacy Principles (APPs). Our aim is to both support and             ♦     directly from you via an email or the internet.
ensure that we comply with these principles. Further information on
privacy in Australia may be obtained by visiting the website of the Office
of the Australian Information Commissioner www.oaic.gov.au
                                                                           How We Use Your Personal Information
Vantage FX believes that this Privacy Policy discloses how the personal
information you provide to us and our representatives, is collected, used,
held, disclosed and disseminated.                                          The information in this document details how we comply with the
                                                                           Privacy Act including:
Vantage FX is required to meet particular legislative and regulatory
requirements which requires us to collect certain personal information           ♦     What is the purpose?
from you for the purposes of:                                                    ♦     Who is my information disclosed to?
                                                                                 ♦     What law requires collection?
      ♦     Providing you with the relevant product or service                   ♦     What are the consequences?
      ♦     Managing and administering the product or service
      ♦     Protecting against fraud                                       Primarily, your personal information is used in order to:
We encourage you to check our website regularly for any updates to our           ♦     Meet particular legislative and regulatory requirements;
Privacy Policy.                                                                  ♦     To assist in providing services to you;
                                                                                 ♦     To assist with any calls you make to us;
                                                                                 ♦     To communicate relevant information to you;
                                                                                 ♦     For our product development, marketing,              planning,
Your Personal Information                                                              administration and credit control procedures..
We are subject to certain legislative and regulatory requirements which    From time to time, we may provide you with direct marketing material.
necessitate us to obtain personal information about you, including s945A   This will include emails, articles and newsletters that may be of interest
of the Corporations Act. Detailed below is some of the information         to you. If, at any time, you do not wish to receive this information any
Vantage FX may hold on you:                                                further, you may contact us with this request. We will endeavour to meet
                                                                           your request within 1 week. We maintain a Register for those individuals
                                                                           not wanting direct marketing material.
      ♦     Name, address, telephone number(s)
      ♦     Date of birth
      ♦     Email address
      ♦     Occupation and job title
                                                                           When We Disclose Your Personal Information
      ♦     Transaction details associated with your trading through us
      ♦     Additional information provided to us and recorded by
            telephone                                                      In line with modern business practices common to many financial
                                                                           institutions and to meet your specific needs we may disclose your
      ♦     Information you provided to us on client agreement forms       personal information to the organisations described below. The
      ♦     Nominated bank account details                                 Corporations Act has provided the Australian Securities and Investments
      ♦     Statement of assets and liabilities                            Commission with the authority to inspect certain personal information
      ♦     Information regarding guarantees of company accounts           that is kept on our files about you. We collect information about you for
                                                                           the purpose of reporting to AUSTRAC under the Anti-Money Laundering
      ♦     Tax file number                                                and Counter-Terrorism Financing Act 2006.
      ♦     Employer
                                                                           For the purposes set out above, we may disclose your personal
If you provide inaccurate or incomplete information we may not be able     information to organisations outside Vantage FX. The organisations to
to provide you with the products or services you are seeking.              which we disclose information may include:
                                                                                 ♦     other product providers in order to manage or administer
                                                                                       your product or service;
Version Date 3.0
Date Prepared: 12th March 2014

      ♦    compliance consultants to ensure that our representatives are    Personal information will be treated as confidential information and
           meeting our compliance standards;                                sensitive information will be treated highly confidential. It is a legislative
                                                                            requirement that we keep all personal information and records for a
      ♦    mailing houses;
                                                                            period of 7 years. Should you cease to be a client of ours, we will
      ♦    your professional advisers, including your solicitor or          maintain your personal information on or off site in a secure manner for
           accountant as authorised by you;                                 7 years. After this, the information will be destroyed.
      ♦    information technology service providers to maintain, review
           and develop our business systems, procedures and
           infrastructure including testing or upgrading our computer
           systems;
      ♦    government and regulatory authorities and other                  Ensure Your Personal Information Is Correct
           organisations, as required or authorised by law, for example,
           to government or regulatory bodies for the purposes related      Vantage FX takes all reasonable precautions to ensure that the personal
           to public health or safety, the prevention or detection of       information we collect, use and disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-
           unlawful activities or to protect public revenue.                date. To ensure we can maintain this level of accuracy and completeness,
      ♦    another authorised representative of Vantage FX if necessary;    we recommend that you:
      ♦    a potential purchaser/organisation involved in the proposed
           sale of our business for the purpose of due diligence,
           corporate re-organisation and transfer or all or part of the
                                                                                  ♦     inform us of any errors in your personal information as soon
                                                                                        as possible; and
           assets of our business.
      ♦    where you have given your consent including your legal
                                                                                  ♦     update us with any changes to your personal information as
                                                                                        soon as possible.
           advisers;
      ♦    a new owner of our business that will require the transfer of
           your personal information.
                                                                            Access to Your Personal Information
In addition, our employees and the outsourcing companies/contractors
are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information      You have a right to access your personal information, subject to certain
held by Vantage FX.                                                         exceptions allowed by law. We ask that you provide your request for
                                                                            access in writing (for security reasons) and we will provide you with
                                                                            access to that personal information. Access to the requested personal
Vantage FX takes its obligations to protect your information seriously,     information may include:
this includes when we operate throughout Australia and overseas, as
part of our operations some uses and disclosures of your information
may occur outside your State or Territory and/or outside of Australia. In         ♦     providing you with copies;
some circumstances we may need to obtain your consent before this                 ♦     providing you with the opportunity for inspection; or
occurs.
                                                                                  ♦     providing you with a summary.
Our ability to enforce the Australian Privacy Principles or any other
contractual privacy obligation against overseas recipients and to take      If charges are applicable in providing access to you, we will disclose these
action in relation to any breach may be very limited and/or far less        charges to you prior to providing you with the information.
effective than it would be if such recipients were Australian based. As
Australian Privacy Principles may not be enforceable against or apply to    Some exceptions exist where we will not provide you with access to your
overseas regulation we understand that you may choose not to                personal information if:
disclosure your personal information to us. However, if you choose not
to provide the information we require to fulfil your request for a specific
product or services, we may not be able to provide you with the                   ♦     providing access would pose a serious threat to the life or
requested product or service.                                                           health of a person;
                                                                                  ♦     providing access would have an unreasonable impact on the
In the event of that we propose to sell the business, we may disclose                   privacy of others;
your personal information to potential purchasers for the purpose of              ♦     the request for access is frivolous or vexatious;
them conducting due diligence investigations. Disclosure will be made in          ♦     the information is related to existing or anticipated legal
confidence and it will be a condition of that disclosure that no personal               proceedings between us and would not be discoverable in
information will be used or disclosed by them.                                          those proceedings;
                                                                                  ♦     providing access would reveal our intentions in relation to
                                                                                        negotiations with you in such a way as to prejudice those
                                                                                        negotiations;
How We Store and Secure Your Personal Information                                 ♦     providing access would be unlawful;
                                                                                  ♦     denying access is required or authorised by or under law;
We keep your personal information in your client file. These files are
                                                                                  ♦     providing access would be likely to prejudice certain
                                                                                        operations by or on behalf of an enforcement body or an
accessible to authorised personnel only and are appropriately secured
                                                                                        enforcement body requests that access not be provided on
out of hours. Your personal information may also be held on our
                                                                                        the grounds of national security.
computer database. All computer-based information is protected
through the use of access passwords. Data is backed up regularly and
stored securely off site. Other measures taken are:                         Should we refuse you access to your personal information, we will
                                                                            provide you with a written explanation for that refusal.
      ♦    Confidentiality requirements for our employees
      ♦    Security measures for systems access
      ♦    Providing a discreet environment for confidential discussions
Version Date 3.0
Date Prepared: 12th March 2014

Using Government Identifiers                                               is saved on your hard disk by your computer's browser. It holds
                                                                           information a site may need to personalise your experience and to
                                                                           gather web site statistical data, such as which pages are visited, what is
Although in certain circumstances we are required to collect government    downloaded, the internet provider's domain name and country that our
identifiers such as your tax file number, Medicare number or pension       visitors come from and the addresses of sites visited immediately before,
card number, we do not use or disclose this information other than         and after, coming to our site. However, none of this is associated with
when required or authorised by law or unless you have voluntarily          you as an individual. It is measured only in aggregate. The information in
consented to disclose this information to any third party.                 the cookies lets us trace your "click stream" activity (i.e., the paths taken
                                                                           by visitors to our site as they move from page to page.) Cookies do not
                                                                           capture your individual email address or any private information about
                                                                           you.
Dealing with us anonymously
                                                                           We also use standard web server log files to help us count visitors and
                                                                           evaluate our site's technical capacity. We use this information to find out
You can deal with us anonymously where it is lawful and practicable to     how many people visit our site, help us arrange the pages in the most
do so. For example, if you telephone requesting our postal address.        user-friendly way, keep the site browser-friendly, and to make our pages
                                                                           more useful to our visitors. We record information on site traffic but not
                                                                           information on individual visitors to our site, so no information about you
                                                                           in particular will be kept or used.
Your sensitive information
                                                                           To browse without cookies, you can configure your browser to reject all
                                                                           cookies, or to notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different,
Without your consent we will not collect information about you that        so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your
reveals your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or     cookie preferences.)
philosophical beliefs or afflations, membership of professional or trade
association, membership of a trade union, details of health, disability,
sexual orientation, or criminal record.
This is subject to some exceptions including:                              Spam Act
      ♦     the collection is required by law; and                         Spam is a generic term used to describe electronic ‘junk mail’- unwanted
                                                                           messages sent to a person’s email account or mobile phone. In Australia,
      ♦     when the information is necessary for the establishment,       spam is defined as ‘unsolicited commercial electronic messages’.
            exercise or defence of a legal claim.
                                                                           ‘Electronic messaging’ covers emails, instant messaging, SMS and other
                                                                           mobile phone messaging, but not cover normal voice-to-voice
Complaints Resolutions                                                     communication by telephone.
Please contact our Privacy Officer if you wish to complain about any       Vantage FX complies with the provisions of the Spam Act when sending
breach or potential breach of your privacy rights. Your complaint will be  commercial electronic messages.
responded to within 7 days. If you are not satisfied with the outcome of
your complaint, you are entitled to contact the Office of the Australian
Information Commissioner.                                                  Equally importantly, Vantage FX makes sure that our practices are in
                                                                           accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles in all activities where
                                                                           they deal with personal information. Personal information includes our
                                                                           clients contact details.
Our Website
Vantage FX website provides links to third party websites. The use of      ‘Do Not Call’ Register
your information by these third party sites is not within the control of
Vantage FX and we cannot accept responsibility for the conduct of these
organisations. Other websites are not subject to our privacy standards,    Unless you call 1300 945 517 and ask us not to contact you about
policies and procedures. You will need to contact or review those          products or services and not to disclose your information to others for
websites directly to ascertain their privacy stands, policies and          that purpose; by accessing our website www.vantagefx.com you consent
procedures.                                                                to us contacting you by telephone while you hold any product or receive
                                                                           any services from us notwithstanding registration at any time of your
                                                                           telephone number on the ‘do not call’ register.
You may register with us to receive newsletters and other information.
By doing so, your name and email address will be collected and stored on
our database. We take care to ensure that the personal information you
give us on our website is protected. For example, our website has
electronic security systems in place, including the use of firewalls and   Internal Procedure for dealing with communications
data encryption.
                                                                           The three key steps Vantage FX follows:
If you do not wish to receive any further information from us, or you wish
to update your registration details, please email your request to us. We
will endeavour to meet your request within 5 working days.                       ♦     Consent – Only commercial electronic messages are sent with
                                                                                       the addressee’s consent – either express or inferred consent.
We may use cookie technology as part of our websites statistical
reporting. A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a website that
Version Date 3.0
Date Prepared: 12th March 2014

      ♦     Identify – Electronic messages will include clear and accurate
            information about the person and the company that is
            responsible for sending the commercial electronic message.
      ♦     Unsubscribe – We ensure that a functional unsubscribe facility
            is included in all our commercial electronic messages and deal
            with unsubscribe requests promptly.
Consented to such communications
Commercial messages will only be sent to you when you have given
consent. This may be express consent – a direct indication that it is okay
to send the message, or messages of that nature or inferred consent
based on our business or other relationship with you and your conduct.
Comply with the law regarding viral messages
Vantage FX ensures that Commercial Communications that include a
Forwarding Facility contain a clear recommendation that the Recipient
should only forward the Commercial Communication to persons with
whom they have a relationship, where that relationship means that
person could be said to have Consented to receiving Commercial
Communications.
Comply with the age sensitive content of commercial
communication
Where the content of a Commercial Communication seeks to promote or
inspire interaction with a product, service or event that is age sensitive,
the Vantage FX takes reasonable steps to ensure that such content is
sent to Recipients who are legally entitled to use or participate in the
product service or event.
Contact Details
Privacy Officer
Vantage FX Pty Ltd
Suite 405, 68 York Street,
Sydney NSW 2000
Phone:      1300 945 517
Fax:        +61 2 9279 2652
Email:      support@vantagefx.com
Version Date 3.0
Date Prepared: 12th March 2014
